<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Choices Story</string>

    <string name="baseStory">

    “Raju! We need you da. 7 on 7. We’re playing against Police Quarters,” Sharan said running towards me. \n
“Sharan sorry da. I have to go get some medicines for my mother. Nana will whip me again if he sees me,” I said. \n
“It’s okay. You are our best player. You know how badly we get beat by them last time yah? We really need you” \n
Cricket was always my passion. And this was perhaps the biggest match the neighborhood would ever see – RG colony vs Police Quarters. This was the match that separated the legends from the boys. I had to be careful, you know. I couldn’t risk being caught by Nana and get another whipping. \n
“Ayoo! Sharan please understand. Don’t ask me again and again. I really want to play but I also have to get medicines for my mother. She’s very sick da” \n
“Raju. Seriously. You know how big this is. 1000 rupees prize money. I will give you 200 if you play. That is much more than that 100 rupees you live on everyday. If you don’t play I will go tell your father that you are bunking class to go play at MCC.” \n


    </string>



    <string name="beatSharanString">

        I couldn’t take it anymore. This fellow had always blackmailed and irritated me since I was a kid. Then it was about doing his math homework and now it was about me playing cricket for the team. I had to put an end to this. \n \n
“Okay, I’ll play,” I said. “Give me the bat” \n
Sharan, the fool, handed the bat over to me, but the moment he passed it on, I took it and started hitting him and his friends with it. \n \n
It is in these situations you have to be prepared for anything, and I learned that the hard way. I ended up with multiple fractures and practically lived in a hospital for the next 3 months of my life. It was fine though – no school and my father wasn’t around to beat me to a pulp because I was already beaten enough to compensate injuries for another few years. It was all good.

    </string>


    <string name="playCricketAgainstPoliceQuartersString">
        I stepped onto the pitch, closed my eyes. \n \n
“Raju! Raju! Raju! Raju!” \n
I could literally hear the scream of the audience. I could see myself donning the blue jersey, playing in front of 100,000 people at the MCG. \n
“Ayy! Raju,” shouted Sharan swatting my head. “Stop dreaming. Play first.” \n \n

Before I could even take strike, I heard the familiar scream from my home. \n
“RAJUU! YOU BLOODY RASCAL. COME HERE RA. YOU HAVE IT IN MY HANDS,” Nana shouted as he came at me, fuming. The whole colony could here his voice. \n
Like every time, I was dragged by my father outside the ground and then back home. It happened so often, I’d forgotten to even feel embarrassed. \n

        “You care about that stupid game more than your mother?! HUH? You’re 18 now. You’re no longer a kid okay. Grow up. When I say I want you to do something you have to do it. I’m not spending money to put you in school for nothing. Study well, get a job. That game isn’t going to give you anything.” \n \n
“But, nana. You never understand. I really want to play. The coach says I can play for India some day. Can studying ever give me that?” \n \n
He slapped me so hard that I couldn’t open my eyes for a few seconds. Everything was blurry. \n
“Listen. You will do what I ask you to. Did you get that job at that paper mill? I’ll take care of the medicines.” \n \n
I couldn’t get myself to say anything more. I was literally shivering. \n
“No…”
THUD! Before I could even finish those words, I was slapped once again. \n
“Get out now. Get that job. Come back. Study. I don’t want to see you on that field again” \n
I ran out of the house like always. I was 18, and legally an adult – but not at home. \n
    </string>

    <string name="getMedicinesString">
        “It’s fine Sharan. You can do what you want. I’m going now.” \n
I started walking out of the colony, when I saw my father running towards me. What was it this time? \n
“RAJUU! YOU BLOODY RASCAL. COME HERE RA. YOU HAVE IT IN MY HANDS,” Nana shouted as he came at me, fuming. The whole colony could here his voice. \n
Like every time, I was dragged by my father outside the ground and then back home. It happened so often, I’d forgotten to even feel embarrassed. \n
“I saw you lingering around the ground. Thinking of playing cricket again ahh? This time I’m never going to let you out again” \n \n

        “You care about that stupid game more than your mother?! HUH? You’re 18 now. You’re no longer a kid okay. Grow up. When I say I want you to do something you have to do it. I’m not spending money to put you in school for nothing. Study well, get a job. That game isn’t going to give you anything.” \n \n
“But, nana. You never understand. I really want to play. The coach says I can play for India some day. Can studying ever give me that?” \n \n
He slapped me so hard that I couldn’t open my eyes for a few seconds. Everything was blurry. \n
“Listen. You will do what I ask you to. Did you get that job at that paper mill? I’ll take care of the medicines.” \n \n
I couldn’t get myself to say anything more. I was literally shivering. \n
“No…”
THUD! Before I could even finish those words, I was slapped once again. \n
“Get out now. Get that job. Come back. Study. I don’t want to see you on that field again” \n
I ran out of the house like always. I was 18, and legally an adult – but not at home. \n

    </string>

    <string name="teaStoreString">

         I couldn’t take my father’s antics anymore. I had to get out of this godforsaken place. So, I did what any sane person would do – I met up with my mates at the chai store and told them all my problems. \n \n
And my friends who were obviously the greatest humans in the world didn’t really give a damn. \n
Frustrated, I bought a lottery ticket at the tea store and waited for 7 days taking all of my father’s abuses.  \n
You thought this was a story about cricket, eh? You couldn’t be more wrong. \n
I won 500,000 Rs. and got the hell out of that place. \n

    </string>

    <string name="paperMillString">
I walked out of the colony and took the local bus to the Times of India paper mill. \n
I saw Morji, the manager standing outside the mill. I told him I wanted a job but he didn’t give me one because he’d already “given them away”. But he offered me a spot on the corporate cricket team. \n
That was the happiest I’d been in days. Cricket could change my life here. I went and spoke to my father, who wasn’t too excited. \n \n
        Before I could explain the whole situation to my father, my mother called me. \n
“Rajuu! Come here da,” my mother called me.  \n
The only person that would understand me was my mother. She’d had cancer and was sick for a long time now, and the doctors said she needed to be operated on to live. My father worked day and night to earn the required money but was always short of earning enough for chemo. \n
“Don’t worry too much about your father da. You should focus on cricket.” \n
“But ma, nana won’t agree…” \n
“He won’t. But that is because he is so stressed nowadays” \n
“Yeah yeah keep feeding his dreams,” said my father steaming into the room.  \n
“You know what, Raju? Sharan spoke to me.” \n
I would have preferred to tell it to him myself, but what had to happen had happened. Sharan’s team probably lost the match and this was his way of getting back at me. \n
“He told me, you’re bunking school to go to MCC academy,” he continued with that stern look on his face. “I can’t take it anymore, get out of my house” \n

    </string>

    <string name="mccCoachingAcademy">

        Now obviously, I wasn’t going to the paper mill. I needed to do some convince my father that cricket was a viable career, and figured the best way to do that would be to play cricket not work at a paper mill, so I ran straight to the MCC coaching academy to meet with my coach, Joseph. \n \n
“Sir! Joseph Sir!” I shouted at him. \n
“What happened ra?” he questioned. \n
“Nothing sir. My father wants me to go back to the paper mill.” \n
“But why did you come to me?” \n
“Because I wanted to ask you if you could talk to my father and convince him” \n
“Hmm. Okay. Listen, I will be at the ground for another hour. So go home and get him to come here, I will talk to him” \n
As I went back home, I passed the colony ground to see a distraught Rohini Gardens team. But for some reason Sharan was smirking at me. My father was waiting right behind the ground and waited for me to approach him to drag me back home.  \n \n
“HOW DARE YOU?! HUH? HOW DARE YOU DISOBEY ME?” he screamed like always.
“You think our family can get by with you playing cricket? With you bunking school? Yeah, Sharan told me everything”  \n \n
I was not only slapped again but was also asked to get out of the house.

    </string>


    <string name="positiveSentimentString">
        “Nana please understand. I really have a chance tomorrow. All I have to do is play well tomorrow and my life is settled. I may even end up playing for India.” \n
“STOP DREAMING!” \n
“But nana. Really. Even if not India I can continue to play for ToI and earn money that way?” \n
“Yes... But for how long? Until you’re 30. And then what?” \n
“Ramesh,” my mother chimed in. “Ramesh, let him go and play. Give him one chance. Please.” \n
My mother wasn’t undergoing chemotherapy. At times I felt like I was putting the family down, but I couldn’t stop playing cricket. But it seemed as if my father would support me this time around. He told me I had one chance to prove myself and the next day, the match was incredible. I stepped onto the field with incredible confidence and played the best game I’d every played. I thought I’d make it into the national squad easily. But as I was stepping out of the ground, I got a call from my friend Lokesh. \n \n
“Raju! Raju! Get to Manati Hospital quick!,” he said frantically. \n
“What happened ra?” \n
“Amma is critical” \n
My mother died of sepsis and that was apparently “expected” in stage 4 cancer. My father didn’t utter a single word for the next four days. On the fifth day, my father came walking towards me with a paper in his hands and threw it on my face. I wasn’t selected. \n

    </string>

    <string name="negativeSentimentString">

        “How long do you think you can control me, huh?” I hit back at him.  \n
“What are you saying?”  \n
“I’m asking you when you’re going to stop taking decisions for me. After I’m married? Or after I’m 50 or something?” \n
I got my school bag and started packing it with a bunch of clothes. \n
My father followed me, awestruck. My mother who could see all this happening got off her bed and rushed behind me. \n
 “Raju, if you leave now, I will not let you come back here again,” my father said. \n
“So be it,” I said and ran out of my house. \n
I felt sad but liberated. I stood against my oppressive father. I went straight to the MCC academy and told my coach everything that had happened. I took up a part-time job to pay for the subsidized room within MCC and started preparing for my game the next day. \n \n
The next day, I stepped onto the field with incredible confidence and played the best game I’d ever played in my life. I’d hit a double hundred and our team cruised to a victory. I knew my time was coming.  But as I was stepping out of the ground, I got a call from my friend Lokesh. \n \n
“Raju! Raju! Get to Manati Hospital quick!” he said frantically. \n
“What happened ra?” \n
“Amma is critical” \n
What started out as a wonderful day turned into a completely dark one, as my mother died of sepsis. The doctors said that was expected in Stage 4 cancer. I took an auto and rushed to the hospital. But as I walked into the hospital my father came rushing out. \n
“AYY aren’t you ashamed of yourself?! How can you even dare to come here da?” he screamed catching hold of my collar. “She died because of you,” he repeated pushing me out of the hospital. I was shaken. I had no idea what to do. I didn’t want to hurt him to much so I walked back to MCC. \n
Four days later, my coach let me know that I wasn’t selected in the U19 squad and I was devastated to say the very least. I had no idea of what to do. \n


    </string>


    <string name="positiveContinueWithCricket">
        “Nana what do you want me to do then?” \n
“Well start going to school and leave the cricket academy. Your one chance is over” \n
“I’m going to continue playing cricket nana” \n
He was staring right into my eyes.  \n
“Get out of my house, and never come back until you earn enough money to keep you settled for the rest of your life.” \n
I didn’t know what to say. \n
“You think I’m kidding? Pack your bags and do what it is you want. Obviously you are above listening to my advice,” he continued, helping me pack my bags.  \n \n
That was the day I left home, devastated. I went to MCC and lived there working part-time to pay for my stay. I waited for another two years – no call back to the Indian team. All along, I never heard from my father – not even a single letter or a phone call and I was too afraid to call him. It seemed like all my effort in the nets on the field never worked. I was deliberating if I should go home or still continue at the academy and play for the state. \n
But one fine day something great happened. \n
“Raju, I’m sorry, but you haven’t been selected,” the coach said. \n
I got so used to rejection that I even forgot how to react. I nodded my head and started walking away. \n
“But wait, Raju. There’s more news. You’ve been selected to play for CSK this IPL season. They’re offering you $350,000 dollars.” \n
It was at that moment that my life changed. \n

    </string>

    <string name="positiveQuitCricket">
        “I don’t know what went wrong nana. Really,” I said as my eyes tearing up. \n
“AY! STOP CRYING. MY WIFE JUST DIED, DO YOU SEE ME CRYING?” he snapped back at me. \n
“I really wanted to do well nana. I don’t know what went wrong” \n
“Well, it doesn’t matter now does it Raju?” he fired back at me. “Now you just have to listen to whatever I say ok?” \n
“Fine nana. Today I’ll quit playing cricket. What do you want me to do?”  \n
“First of all, stop going to MCC. And next, I want you to study really hard. Your mother isn’t alive anymore, so you don’t have to work. The money I’m earning is enough to feed two people. So I want you to go to school properly from now on. Clear your board exams first.”  \n
“Okay, nana”. \n
It was a decision that changed my life. I started becoming more responsible, and for once, listening to my father benefited me. My mother used to always say that my father was rude but that he cared. \n
But it all ended well, for I turned into a commentator. \n


    </string>


    <string name="negativePlayCricket">
        My mother had so much hope in me, and I had to fulfill her wishes. So I continued to play cricket even harder. My routine went like this – play cricket early in the morning, have some food, play cricket again, work at the MCC, go back to the room and cry. \n \n
No matter how hard I played, I never got a call from the selectors. I waited for another two years – no call for the Indian team. All along, I never heard from my father – not even a single letter or a phone call and I was too afraid to call him. It seemed like all my effort in the nets on the field never worked. I was always lacking some skill and my form was dipping as I grew older. I was 20 now and was growing older. \n \n
Nothing worked out.

    </string>

    <string name="negativeBecomeCoach">

        My mother had so much hope in me, and I had to fulfill her wishes. So I continued to play
        cricket even harder. My routine went like this – play cricket early in the morning, have
        some food, play cricket again, work at the MCC, go back to the room and cry. \n
        No matter how hard I played, I never got a call from the selectors. I waited for another two
        years – no call for the Indian team. All along, I never heard from my father – not even a
        single letter or a phone call and I was too afraid to call him. It seemed like all my effort
        in the nets on the field never worked. I was always lacking some skill and my form was
        dipping as I grew older. I was 20 now and was growing older. \n \n
        Nothing worked out, and I was now too old to go to college. But amidst bad news, I got an
        offer from the MCC to start out as an assistant coach, which I then accepted. \n
        Cricket had taken everything from me but was also the only reason I was employed. \n
        I wanted to contact my father – so I called him after 4 years, but his number wasn’t
        reachable. So I went home only to see that he wasn’t there as well. \n
        All my familial ties were severed, but at least, I’d gotten a fresh start. \n


    </string>


</resources>
